

Urvi Nikhil Kumar Date of Birth: 17th May 1998 Contact Details: Phone Number: +91 75501 70247

urvinikhilkumar@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/urvi-kumar-13a78ba7/

# **About Me**

My fields of interest are Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Science and Analytics, Big Data, and Cryptography. I have experience in Robot Process Automation, Machine Learning, Development, Android Software Application Development, Web Application Designing, and Migration. I am fascinated by how Machine Learning applications in Big Data problems can result in well-defined patterns and many unnoticed interpretations. I would like to leverage my technical knowledge and management skills across various fields. I am an inquisitive person; I like to learn new things.

#### **Achievements**

- Merit Based Scholarship academic year 2018-2019 and 2019-2020 from SRM Institute of Science and Technology
- o Letter of Recommendation from Career Development Center SRM Institute of Science and Technology
- Certificate of Appreciation outstanding performance Extempore

#### Workshops and Conferences

- National Workshop on Machine Learning
- National Workshop on Software Reliability Engineering
- Developing Applications for Android Platform
- Virtual Reality Workshop
- SRM Model United **Nations** conference

## **Education**



SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Kattankulathur, (Deemed to be University) Bachelor of Technology (Information

Technology)

CGPA (Running):8.6 SGPA: (1st- 7th Sem): 8.2, 8.17, 8.5, 9.52,8.5,8.12,9.2

May 2016 to Present



Indira National School, Pune

✓ HSC-CBSE PCMB

Percentage:72.8% 2014 to 2016



**Spicer Higher Secondary School** 

SSC-ICSE

Percentage:89.2%

2009 to 2014

## **Work Experience**



RPA Developer (Intern)

Cleartrip.com, Bangalore Dec 2019 to Present

Domain: Robotic Process Automation



**Automation Testing Engineer (Intern)** 

T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune May 2019 to June 2019

Domain: API Automation Testing



**Machine Learning Intern** 

Mindzen. Chennai mindZen

November 2018 to January 2019 Domain: Machine Learning, ChatBot



ChatBot Developer (Intern)

T-Systems ICT LTD PVT. Pune June 2018 to July 2018

Domain: Machine Learning, ChatBot



**Student Associate** 

SRM University CARE, Pune May 2017 to August 2017

Domain: Auto Evaluation eLab Learning Tool



Web Developer (Intern)

T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune December 2016 to January 2017 Domain: Web Development with Cloud

## **Project Details:**

- Developing API Automation Testing Protocol for Developers Tools: AWS Elastic Search, Postman, Newman, Jenkins In Association with: T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune
- Anti-Submergence Application Tools: Arduino, Android Studio, MQTT Self-Developed Project
- Crime Registration Portal with Number Plate, Object and Face Recognition Image Processing, Web Development Self-Developed Project
- Marketing Campaign Optimization with SQL Server R Services

Tools: SQL Server, R, Power BI Link: <a href="https://goo.gl/bPPH7m">https://goo.gl/bPPH7m</a> Self-Developed Project

Length of Stay Predicting Model

Tools: SQL Server, Python, Microsoft Machine Learning Server, Power BI

Link <a href="https://goo.gl/VUetHP">https://goo.gl/VUetHP</a> Self-Developed Project

Vehicle Telemetric Analysis

Tools :Python, R, Azure, Azure Machine Learning Studio, Azure Stream Analytics, Azure

**Data Factory** 

In Association with: T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune

> Translation Chat Bot

Tools: Node.js IIS Express, Azure BotBuilder In Association with: T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune

Multilingual QnA Chat Bot

Tools :Node.js, Azure BotBuilder, QnA Maker

In Association with: T-Systems ICT LTD PVT, Pune

➤ Motor Insurance Claim Chat Bot

Tools: Node.js, Dialogue Flow

In Association with: Mindzen, Chennai